Please contact us for any inquiries
turkision@gmail.com
NO ANIMALS WERE HARMED DURING
THE FILMING OF THIS PRODUCTION.
Soldiers! Arrest Osman!
Alişar Bey!
How could you take a Bey's
son from a Bey's Tent?
You are standing in
front of a banner lord.
Sheathe that dagger.
You put down your blades too.
I will bathe this Tent with the
blood of your soldiers, Alişar Bey!
Get away from my brother!
Stand back, Gürbüz!
Don't make me hurt you too!
How did you find out
Kalonoz was dead, Alişar Bey?
I was in the castle.
They told me the killers
of Kalonoz were the Kayıs.
Dündar Bey, who are they to
talk while you stand there?
We...
... are the Kayı, Alişar Bey.
We know no will than Allah's and
no chairmanship than His messenger's.
Dündar Bey...
... think thoroughly.
This ends either by
mass execution or by exile.
Wouldn't the Mongol you are
loyal to ask you about this?
We say Osman is innocent,
don't you understand?
You are attacking us
because of Kulucahisar!
Neither them nor you!
- I only care about justice.
- If you are the banner lord...
... then you should've looked after us.
You shouldn't have
come here unnoticed.
Enough, Osman. I won't
learn manners from you.
I can take all of your heads right now!
What do you think you are doing here?
Osman killed Kalonoz, he's going
to pay for it, now move aside.
Don't you know that we
won't give Osman to you?
Are you going to stop me?
Move!
Is it tradition to ambush
Bey's Tent, to draw swords?
We aren't ambushing the Tent,
Abdurrahman Gazi, we are doing our duties.
If you are innocent, why are you
standing behind the swords?
Do you fear my inquiry?
I don't fear anything that I can see.
But I fear treachery, Alişar Bey.
Do you think I will sacrifice
you for an infidel woman?
I will establish a fair trial.
Osman, there are Byzantine,
Mongols, I don't want any more trouble.
Make up your mind.
I am not afraid of your
trial or your judgment.
But...
... I would want to speak
to Sofia face to face.
Osman, don't you trust this man.
Osman, you don't have to go, my nephew.
We will defend you until Kayı's last
sword, until our last drop of blood.
Both I and my weapon
are on your hands, Alişar Bey.
Alişar Bey, New Bazaar was attacked last
night, our men were slaughtered.
Who did this, Nizamettin?
I will go to the New Bazaar too.
Take him to the mansion,
he will wait in a cell until I return.
Osman Bey.
Soldiers!
Is it better to fear death,
or wait for the death, Bala?
It was your first dhikr.
I don't know my Sheikh.
Sultan of the brave men, Hz. Hamza...
... started to appear in the battles
without an armor near his death.
This move didn't go unnoticed
between the people.
Some of them asked: "Oh, master of
swordsmanship didn't you read...
... Allah's "do not throw [yourselves] with
your [own] hands into destruction" surah?"
Surah Al-Baqarah [2:195]
Hz. Hamza answered with wisdom.
"When I was young, I saw death
as a goodbye to this world.
When I was enlightened with
my nephew Hz. Muhammed's light...
... I understood.
That the "do not throw [yourselves] with
your [own] hands into destruction" surah...
... is for the ones who
see death as a danger."
Thus, death is not an end. It is a beginning
about the opening of the gate of truth.
If we know it like this, we would be
waiting for death, not fearing it.
In this period of time, the ones who
will open the gates of conquests...
... won't be the ones who fear death...
... but will be the ones who come from
Hz. Hamza, who killed death itself.
How good those soldiers are, for they are
not afraid of losing their lives or wealth.
How good those soldiers are, for they
don't choose their desires over their fights.
How good those soldiers are, for their
names will be...
... given to a generation, an age, a soul.
Who do you think you are fooling?
Do you think you can get away
from me with your lies?
I earned your wrath.
I only wish to be a Muslim
in my last breath.
You martyred my Aybars, you burned
my heart, you killed my son!
My life is on your hands, Bamsı
Bey. But if you spare me...
... I will be a son to you until I die.
Please, give your blessings to me.
I took your son from you, Bamsı Bey.
Do what needs to be done.
Killing Kulucahisar's general...
... and throwing his body in front
of the castle like an animal, huh?
I will make you pay such a price...
... that everyone will
hear about it, Osman.
First Osman, then all of the Kayı.
After them, every single
one of the Turks...
... I will rip every one of their
hearts and feed it to the dogs!
I swear, not only for Kalonoz...
...I will kill tens of Turks for every
one of our soldiers that we've lost!
Alişar Bey must've taken
Osman from his Tent.
We can't touch Kayıs before he's dead.
Even if Alişar Bey took Osman from
the Kayıs, he can't hold him for long.
Osman will find a way to break free.
Samsa Bey.
Don't let us spill our
brothers' blood, Zorba.
Let Osman Bey go.
We are just obeying orders, Samsa Bey.
Don't make this hard for us.
Well then, if anyone wants to draw
their last breath, take up your swords!
I said it once, I won't
say it again, Zorba!
Then come and take him!
Brothers!
Put down your swords.
Don't make Alps angry.
You will get yourselves killed.
Don't make these brave men's
knots tight, Brother Bora.
Or they will die here.
On your command, my Bey!
Thank you, Sergeant Samsa.
I can't wait to watch Osman die.
You are right, but we should prepare
our game, in case he gets away.
My informant Nizamettin brought
me very important news.
Alişar fell in love with
Edebali's daughter.
Only this is enough to make
Alişar and Osman fight each other.
But don't forget, if Osman gave in
to Alişar, he must have a plan.
We must tread very carefully.
Isn't there any word from Salvador yet?
No, sir.
"I bear witness that there is no deity but Allah, and I bear witness that Muhammad is the messenger of Allah."
"I bear witness that there
is no deity but Allah...
... and I bear witness...
...that Muhammad is the
messenger of Allah."
What are we going to do now, Osman bey?
Alişar Bey has been taking gold from
Konya, under the Mongol invasion.
I heard while soldiers were talking.
Then, it is loot time, my Bey.
Alişar Bey's gold is halal for those
who worry about the Turks, Osman Bey.
Turks' destiny will be determined not by
the ones who take gold from the enemy...
... but by the ones who sacrifice their
lives and their wealth for this cause.
Sergeant Samsa.
Tell Abdurrahman Gazi. You should take
over the gold with the Alps at once.
But, don't let anyone
know it was us for now.
Don't you worry, Osman Bey.
- Brother Konur, what about Samsa Bey?
- He hasn't returned yet, my Bey.
Let's go here before he kills Salvador.
He has the key to Sofia.
May our fortune be good!
- Allah is Great!
- Allah is One!
Hatuns, I don't want Tent's morale to
be low because of Alişar's doings.
You are responsible for
women's happiness and order.
Idiot.
He made friends with Kulucahisar,
he's accompanying them like a dog.
Don't worry, Dündar Bey.
He has gone too far with his last doings.
He slapped my Batur, we stood silent.
But when it is Osman, he has gone too far!
You...
... see a slap when you look.
But I see migration roads,
exiles, taken heads.
Of course we didn't stand silent.
Of course, we had his name on the list.
You, you should wait.
We've become mute waiting like that!
He slapped my valiant boy
like a child in the square.
I feel sorrow when I think about it.
Zöhre, don't you know us, do you
think Alişar will get away with that slap?
Is Batur missing something from Osman?
Is Osman different from Batur,
that we would separate them?
Both Osman and Batur are our children.
Thank you Selcan Hatun, thank you.
It's like you said, of course.
If we say stop, we say have patience.
When the time comes, Kayı's weapons will
cut those hands that slap and chain!
Let it be known like this.
Peace be upon you, Sheikh Edebali.
Peace be upon you too, what is it...
... with all these men, Alişar Bey?
Our existence is an example of order.
We are here for order.
Bad things happened at night time.
Do you know anything about it?
- Good news?
- A few of my men were killed...
... by the bandits who attacked
the bazaar.
Have you heard anything about this?
Ablution will cleanse your sins.
Now, wash inside of your ears with
your little fingers...
... back of your neck with the back
of your hand...
... and then your feet.
- May Allah accept it.
- May you live long, Osman. Thank you
Here.
Guys, before you ask...
... I'll tell you.
Just like Wahshi, who killed...
... our prophet Hz. Muhammed's uncle
Hz. Hamza...
... saw reason and became Hz. Wahshi.
- But my Bey!
- Konur! Konur! Konur Alp! Listen to me!
Listen to me! Listen to me!
My son Aybars was a valiant.
He was a valiant.
But was he such a valiant like Prophet
Mohammad's...
... uncle Hz. Hamza was?
Our Prophet...
... forgave his uncle's killer.
I am a poor Bamsı Beyrek.
As long as there are valiants like you,
who can hinder our cause, Bamsı Bey?
My Osman...
My Bey, what if this infidel is lying
because he fears death?
We'll figure it out now.
His first trial will be harsh.
May Allah forgive their mistakes.
We sleep early and wake up early.
That's what Prophets do.
Interesting. We thought you stay awake
in your sleep...
... alert, and sharp-sighted.
Then you probably don't know that
Osman Bey killed Kalonoz.
Why does the death of a known
infidel like Kalonoz's death...
... disturb you so much, Alişar Bey?
Don't assume I don't know that
you're working with Osman.
I'm asking if you have anything to do
with this incident or not.
Being side by side with a valiant
like Osman is happiness.
I can't say anything about how bold he is.
But he is his own master.
Eagles cannot be caged, lions don't
fit into the jungle, Alişar Bey.
These lands' order is my business.
I don't care about lions or eagles.
The Mongol in Konya doesn't want disorder.
Allah knows what really happened
at night, Alişar Bey.
But I know this.
If you add water to the soil,
it becomes mud...
If you add blood,
it becomes your homeland.
If Osman killed that infidel,
well done to him.
He is a great valiant.
Why is that gillyflower upset?
It's thirsty I suppose.
No one thought about watering it.
It faded away.
May it be easy, ladies.
I've been wanting to decorate my
mansion's walls with chinas.
And I don't know anyone more talented
than you.
Besides, what does our religion say?
"Hire those who deserve it."
The same verse continues with
"When you rule, rule with justice."
Isn't Bala Hatun's companionship
a grace, Gonca Hatun?
Her knowledge, her skills...
How wonderful!
I'll definitely trust you with
my mansion, Bala Hatun.
When our skilful Ahis arrive, you can
speak to them about this, Alişar Bey.
I don't paint mansion walls.
Alişar Bey.
What, Nizamettin?
Kayı's Alps rescued Osman Bey from
the soldiers.
What the hell are you talking about?
- I'll pour it, my Sheikh.
- May you live long, my daughter.
- My Sheikh?
- Yes, my daughter?
Nizamettin brought some news as
Alişar Bey was leaving.
He said Osman ran away from the soldiers.
Alişar Bey got angry and left. What is
happening my Sheikh?
Alişar Bey arrested Osman Bey
for killing Kalonoz.
Arrested him?
So Osman Bey ran away from them.
He surely knows something.
What if something happens to
Osman Bey, my Sheikh?
Bala!
Since when do we worry about people?
Allah knows what will happen.
Instead of worrying about Osman...
... you shall mind your own business.
Don't get involved!
Pour some more.
the Mongols have come to the
caravansary, Madam.
You seem to take good care of your fish.
They need me.
Taking care of those who need me,
is in my nature.
Under your stiff looks...
... there is a kind spirit, Alişar Bey.
Just like these fish, you live in a small
pond called Kulucahisar.
My kindness is also for you.
As much as we needed your kindness...
... surely you needed us.
Princess...
For a smile of yours, for a nice word...
... I've opened doors in my lands bigger
than you can imagine.
If you want to trade, we will
until the end.
If you want Osman, just ask
and I'll skin him.
If a single mistake, a single shadow
comes between us...
Your soldiers haven't brought
Osman Bey yet.
I hope he didn't slip through
your fingers.
Alişar Bey.
Damn it!
Salvador! Go to Master Yannis now!
Tell him that Princess Sofia fell into
Osmans trap. Now!
Where are my soldiers?
I've loosened the ropes. They will be
here shortly.
Why shouldn't I hang you with those ropes?
Soldiers!
Revolt against my rule, huh?
With your boldness, you've
asked for your death.
I've come because I had faith in
your fairness, Alişar Bey.
And now, I give in to your fairness.
What do these mean, Alişar Bey?
What is it, Sofia?
Don't you remember Salvador?
I'm seeing this man for
the first time in my life.
Is that so?
Let me remind you then.
Salvador, leader of the Catalans...
... who attacked New Bazaar under you
and your father's command.
- Is that true, Sofia?
- How can you believe Osman's lies?
- How can you prove yourself?
- Alişar Bey!
All the gold we got from attacking
your Bazaar...
... are still in my secret place.
I'm ready to go there with your soldiers
and give them back to you.
But Salvador still has some things
to say, Alişar Bey.
There's still lots of things you'll hear.
Enough!
I can't stand this shamelessness anymore!
I'm leaving.
Wait for a second, Sofia.
You wanted a court, here it is.
- Soldiers!
- Betrayal!
Alişar Bey!
Alişar Bey.
Osman.
Leave her alone.
I want to learn everything you know.
Tell me everything.
I've been walking for two days.
I'm hungry. Please, a piece of bread.
Take a seat.
- Thanks, brother.
- He can't hear you. He's mute and deaf.
Prepare a meal for us!
And take four servings to the room!
Okay.
Abdurrahman Gazi. You take care of the
ones inside with Erkut Alp.
The gold is probably in the room. We'll go
to the room with Boğaç brother.
You know what to do.
Let them attack first.
Good luck.
What do you think you're doing?
I'll strangle you!
He's mine.
He stole my stuff!
So Yorgopolos' killers are
Sofia and Kalonoz.
Is that correct?
A bandit Osman Bey bought with gold...
... is slandering me while hiding
behind your holy religion.
Will you still keep silent, Alişar Bey?
Your dreams with Yannis will be crushed
under Kulucahisar's debris, Sofia!
I have witnessed everything.
I am ready to witness in the presence of
Emperor.
There are so many evidence to prove
in the castle.
We just need to get through the walls,
Alişar Bey.
When this vile game ends and
you come back to my castle...
you'll fear Emperor's anger, Alişar.
You too, Salvador.
You'll be sorry.
I would be honored to die.
I will die as a martyr, Sofia.
This game ends here.
Kill me, or let me go, Alişar Bey!
There is a lot to talk about.
Soldiers!
Take her to the dungeon!
Get your hands off me!
Get off!
I'll see you and your tent again, Osman!
Alişar Bey.
Salvador is a Muslim now.
He is under my protection. If you allow,
he can bring the new bazaar's golds.
I trust your words, Osman Bey.
Bamsı Bey, set off immediately.
Eyvallah(okay), my Osman.
This is for you.
Leave the food and get out.
Now!
Ignoble Alişar!
He lost his faith to reach the infidel's
gold!
He is trying to rule the Turks with
their gold!
Your turn will come!
Alişar Bey will kill me.
Sofia fooled all of us.
She fooled us with her poisoned tongue.
If you were like the old...
Alişar Bey, I would tell you everything.
However, you were stunned by Sofia and
you wouldn't have understood me...
even if I'd told you.
Everything was to protect our land.
- Sofia poisoned all of us.
- Not only Sofia.
Also his father Yannis did.
I'll take him from that castle.
Either they give him to me right away,
or I'll do it by force, Yannis!
Believe me.
Listen to me very carefully, Alişar Bey.
Sofia is not just the wife of a Tekfur...
And Yannis is not just a random monk.
Osman Bey, you are not only a
valiant Alp...
but also a strong and wise Bey.
I will rule this land with Beys like you.
What I don't understand is, how come
Sheik Edebalı didn't accept you as a groom?
You are like my brother, Osman Bey.
I know you love Bala Hatun.
What are you going to do?
Tell me.
No one can keep me here!
Do you hear me?
Sheik Edebalı is a great scholar.
There must be a reason to refuse a
Kayı Bey...
who faced sufferings for his daughter.
My Bey, Mongols who were carrying the
golds were killed.
What are you talking about?
What do you mean they were killed?
Who dares to do this in my land?
- My Bey...
- What about the gold?
They took the gold, my Bey.
Gather the soldiers!
Search everywhere!
I'll go to the caravanserai.
Get my horse ready, now!
Treason is all over us, Osman Bey.
I'll make those traitors pay!
Don't panic, Alişar Bey.
I'll be on your side when we destroy
the traitor in the Kulucahisar Castle.
Wild dogs!
They think they can stop me by taking
Sofia.
Get my daughter out of that dungeon,
Nizamettin. You know Alişar's mansion well.
- We'll do our best with Helen, sir.
- If something happens to my daughter...
I'll burn you with that mansion!
I will not let any harm touch
Sofia, sir.
Show them who Yannis is!
My bird.
What did you bring me?
Osman's alps.
They got into the caravansarai.
They stole the gold that Mongols
brought to Alişar Bey, Efendi Yannis.
You will take your own life while
trying to kill my daughter, Osman.
Leave!
- What do you think, sir.
- I will meet Alişar in the Caravansarai.
I have heard that...
my father will do appointments, brother.
Who works hard is awarded, my Batur.
Obviously my uncle wants people to work.
I wonder...
where he will appoint everyone.
In Kayı tradition, you don't want a
mission, a mission is given to you.
The valiant who takes the mission
completes it.
That's right.
You're tired, brother. Trading on one hand,
being Head Alp in the other.
What now, my Batur?
Do you want to be the Head Alp?
I didn't mean it, brother. I said it
because you are busy.
Let the joke aside...
Being Head Alp is a hard mission,
my Batur.
Even in Kayı, it is harder.
The mission should be given to a valiant
who is brave like you.
Eyvallah (thank you) brother.
Eyvallah.
However, brave young men cannot succeed
every time, but you do.
If my father will do as we say...
I think he may appoint you as his
assistant because you are experienced.
Hope the best, my Batur.
Hope the best.
Where were you while my men were
being killed...
in the day time?
My Bey, it happened suddenly.
I didn't see anything.
You work in my land...
but you don't see while they
steal my gold!
- Take him! a hundred whips!
- Forgive, my Bey, please.
I am not done with you!
No one saw or heard about you.
Don't they know about my anger?
I will find them even if the ground
swallows them.
I will find them!
Some can see the invisible, and hear
the inaudible.
Who are you, old man?
My name is Astrologer Abdül, my Bey.
I can see the deep.
I see the future.
Take him out!
You are looking for who did this!
Stop!
There are eyes which can see but
cannot talk.
What are you talking about, old man?
Say what you have to say!
Deaf and mute.
But he sees like an eagle!
Who is that?
My Bey, there is a poor around here.
- Where is he?
- He lives in the yard.
Bring him to me immediately!
Eat!
This is your last meal.
Who did this?
Are you ready to see the truth,
Alişar Bey?
Kayıs!
Take him out.
So, Abdul.
We have never heard of you.
We are having a lot of trouble.
May you bring good news, old man.
This gold glints.
However, your fate is dark.
I see a mansion.
Beyond misty roads and gauzy hills.
A great mansion.
And a prisoner who is getting ready to
escape.
Delicate like a flower...
but wild inside, a prisoner.
You see the deep, old man.
But you miss one thing.
My mansion is more secure than
the Emperor's castle in Constantinopolis.
Don't forget, Alişar Bey.
The chain holds the prisoner.
But treason breaks the order!
While all of my men guards...
a prisoner aside, even a soul cannot
get out of there.
Just remember my words, Alişar Bey.
If you seek for help...
I will be in the cave in Kartalkaya.
What's up, princess?
Didn't you like it?
It's not like the castle's food, right?
More power to you Bala Hatun.
Do it yourself, if it's easy Aygül Hatun.
Your job is hard.
You make two jugs and sweat blood...
...just to gain some money.
The point is gaining honestly,
Aygül Hatun.
A despiser eye would not see
the beauty or effort.
To see beauty, you should look well.
Give me two jugs from there.
Let us play a role in your earning.
I cannot take your money, Burçin Hatun.
What does that mean?
Don't you like us?
I didn't mean it.
We respect Osman Bey very much.
We can't sell you anything, we can
only gift.
Accept it, Aygül Hatun.
I painted it on my own.
Something happened
that made me really happy.
That's why its colours are this vivid.
It's my gift to you.
As-salamu alaykum.
(Peace be unto you)
Alaikum salam.
(Peace be unto you too)
Bala Hatun...
...Osman Bey wants to see you.
He has something to say.
Bala...
... my Sheikh would not want
you to meet him.
Don't you know it?
Will you really go?
Osman Bey is in trouble because of us.
My father doesn't want to see him either.
If it wasn't important,
Osman Bey wouldn't want to see me, Gonca.
I should go and learn it.
See you.
What a pity!
It's broken now.
Don't be upset.
There are much better ones.
Not much effort was put into it anyway.
Osman...
...luckily I could see you unhurt.
My beautiful.
My gracious love.
My sun.
I ate my heart out.
Tell me.
What's going on Osman?
The snake Sofia is at the place
that she deserves.
In Alişar's dungeon.
The infidels will stay away from you
for a whlie.
But I don't know how long it
will be like this.
But we should be awake.
Alişar is giddy-paced, he is unreliable.
He is ignoble and it's really clear.
We won't trust him.
Don't worry.
What is bothering your heart, Bala?
Tell me.
Osman...
...while we're waiting with patience...
...what if another aspirant comes up?
If my father finds it proper...
...I'm afraid Osman.
Your name is sealed to my heart Bala.
I will never love someone else, and
I will never let anybody else love you.
Don't be afraid.
Till I smell your silky hair...
...wear this kerchief.
Any time that I pray to Allah, there is
always your name in my lips.
My pray is that, he gives us to each other
for lifelong.
Inshallah.
May Allah help you.
My prayers are with you.
But my father doesn't want us
to see each other.
From now on, don't call me.
I understand.
I understand, Bala.
Don't bother your heart.
Just pray.
Your prayer is my armor.
Father!
My daughter.
The dog that called Osman
did it again!
Fortunately, your father put
a servant...
...next to everyone who may hurt you.
Father.
After he learns that I escaped,
Alişar Bey will come after me.
How will we stop him?
Alişar Bey met Abdül.
Abdül already told him that
his captive will escape.
Who is Abdül?
The Chaldean
who will make Alişar our puppet.
His one name is Abdül,
and the other name is...
Yannis.
May Allah accept it, father.
Inshallah, my daughter.
Pick up your foods, little lives.
Pick them up.
They are too many to count.
But...
... there is one in the lead.
Wherever it goes, the others follow him.
And you Bala?
Are you like ants?
You have something to tell me.
Say it.
My Sheikh.
If you allow it, I would like to tell you
what Osman Bey is doing.
Firstly, tell me, my daughter Bala.
How do you know what Osman Bey is doing?
My Sheikh...
...you don't accept Osman Bey...
...he told me to inform you.
Sofia is in a dungeon thanks to him.
The infidels won't bother us for a while.
He told you can concentrate
on your trading...
...but stay alert.
How can you meet Osman while you
know that I don't allow it, Bala?
Is it my daughter?
- My Sheikh--
- I'm asking again!
Is the one who ignored me,
who did what I didn't allow...
...who ignored my permission...
... you?
Silence...
...comes from admission.
It's clearly you.
Obviously you...
...don't care about our words...
...you follow your own truths.
Father...
...don't say that.
Now go and think, Bala.
Think, so you correct your mistake
before we separate from being ourselves.
Thanks to Allah we're full.
May Allah give to those who need it.
Amin.
When will we solve his circumcision issue
Bamsı Bey?
Which circumcise?
Do you think to be a Muslim is that easy?
You'll lie down under the knife.
Under the knife!
My sons.
Let's solve this issue tomorrow.
Tomorrow?
What do you mean tomorrow?
Bamsı Bey...
...will his name stay as Salvador?
My Osman...
From now on, your name is...
...Ebubekir Sıddık.
Ebubekir Sıddık.
Be loyal to your religion.
Know it like this, children.
Thank you.
We'll get the booty first.
We'll sacrifice lots of goats to celebrate
Sıddık's circumcision.
Right, Bamsı Bey?
Thank you, Konur Alp. Thank you.
My Osman, what will you do
with that much booty?
No matter Muslim or not...
...we will give them to all poor people.
We'll give them to be hope for
all the world.
Mashallah to my Osman.
Boran brother.
Play us your dombra!
Cheer us up.
As you wish, my Bey.
Mashallah to my brave man.
Mashallah.
Thank you, my Bey.
Bala...
...look, today I bought those threads.
They will become very beautiful
things in your hands.
Look at these beautiful blue and green.
Bala?
Bala.
Don't be upset.
Don't worry.
Everything will be okay.
Will it be okay Gonca?
Do you think my father's anger
will vanish?
Sure it will vanish.
Don't you know how much he loves you?
I know.
This is why I'm afraid.
I ignored his word.
My father won't forgive me easily.
Until I find a way to make him forgive me,
each breath will hurt me, Gonca.
How can she escape from the dungeon, from
the hands...
... of my own soldiers.
How?
I asked you.
How could she escape?
My Bey, this is done by someone
from inside.
There is no other explanation.
Are you aware of your words?
This is betrayal.
The chain holds the captive...
...but betrayal breaks the system.
There is an chaldean in caravansary...
...in the cave in Kartalkaynı.
His name is Abdül.
Find and bring him to me
righ now.
I'll do as you order, my Bey.
Your body is here but your mind is
somewhere else, my Bey.
What are you thinking that deeply?
I'm thinking about my Tent's
future, Hatun.
I'm thinking about my
heart's flower Aygül.
What about Aygül?
Alişar is attacking his own kind with
the word of the enemy.
He's doing wrong to us because of an
infidel's word.
On top of it...
He comes to my tent and slaps my
son.
Aygül, my sweet rose.
I refuse my daughter to fade out in
Alişar's garden.
I'll solve this circle.
Tomorrow's meeting is important.
You have an idea but you're not telling
it.
Then I'll tell you, my Zöhre.
From now on there will be a new order in
the Tent.
We'll be such an order that even Mongol...
...won't make difference, not just Alişar.
I have my nephew on my one side...
...my son, Batur on the other side.
And mighty Osman on my back.
Osman.
My Bey, do you hear yourself?
I do, Hatun.
I do.
Tomorrow I'll give him such
a duty that...
... it will both change his
position in the Tent...
...and his responsibility will
get heavier, but...
... I know that he'll succeed.
You're relying on a mad man like Osman.
My Bey, if you ask me, I'll say think
about it again.
There's nothing to think
about, Hatun.
Tomorrow, after giving his duty...
...I'll want such a thing from him that...
...it will bond him more and more to
our Tent and our family.
And will restrain his madness.
So we will ride out the storm.
Then no one will be able to
stand against us.
Say it, my son.
What makes you upset?
It's for sure, you have a problem.
Yes, I do.
I have a problem.
Say it. Let me take care of it.
Talk to Aygül. She shouldn't marry Alişar.
My uncle won't marry them without Aygül's
consent.
Talk her out of this.
He acts differently to Mongols and
infidels!
May devil take him.
Any kind of malice would come from him.
He's going to take our girl and get in our
family, tent.
What should we do aunt? Should we lay a
bed for this evil?
This isn't a love affair.
This is political affair.
You're right but it's improper.
We can't do anything if she's
okay with it.
You're right, aunt.
You're right.
If this infidel takes Aygül...
...not just our family, our tent will be
fouled as well.
He'll ruin everything.
I would prevent it if I can.
But, you're right aunt.
Without Aygül's consent, we can't do
anything.
My wrathful but merciful, Osman.
May Allah reward you.
Tell me about your heart. What's happening
there?
My one side is like delirious storms.
Wants to go over mountains, plains.
And the other side...
...like I have fallen appart.
I have no strength left.
The heart wants its lover to be nearby.
When someone can't meet their loved one...
... they can't relax.
I'll bring Bala here, my aunt.
I'm waiting. Sheikh Edebali didn't
allow it yet.
Maybe one day he'll allow it.
I'll call him father and kiss his hand.
Hopefully, my son.
Hopefully.
In the ninety-nine names of Allah...
...who has the power to create...
...and who fills our hearts with faith.
Bismillahirrahmanirrahim. (In the name
of Allah, the compassionate, the merciful)
Valiant Beys of Kayı.
We need to refresh ourselves
to stay alive.
Because of this, I'm thinking about a new
duty arrangements...
...as Kayı Bey's deputy.
Kayı's markets...
... caravans and gold...
... will be held responsible from my
nephew Gündüz...
...which I have never doubt of his morals.
As you order, my Bey.
Soldiery needs valiantness...
...valiantness needs bravery.
Head of Kayı Alps will be...
...my dear son, Batur Bey.
Thank you, my Bey father.
With the arrival of Selcan Hatun's tent,
our numbers will increase.
It's not easy to rule a tent.
It needs to have morals, Bey's attitude...
...and know about Kayı.
Because of that, I held my nephew Osman...
... responsible as my Lead Assistant...
... who grew up in my brother's tent.
Order is yours, my Bey.
These our new duties that given...
...for our magnificent tent...
...and our fertile land.
Thank you, my Bey.
My hunting fellows!
My young scouts!
We will start the hunting season
early this year.
Before the flowers bloom...
Before the young ones stop sucking milk...
The blood season has come.
My anger shall be engraved on the
Sultan's shadow Alişar Bey's banner...
... on it's water, on it's soil, it's
rocks.
Those who hurt me should know that
I'll hurt them more!
Those who burn my heart should know that
I'll turn their Tents into ashes!
Now go and spit blood on them!
Show them the power of Alişar Bey!
You'll take Kayıs down when you see them!
What is it, Ayşe Hatun. You look like
you're looking at something beautiful.
I'm looking at my valiant.
I cheer up the more I look, my Gündüz.
I wish your ancestor Süleyman Şah
could see your magnificence.
My sunlight...
... my Ayşe...
If a valiant came out of this Gündüz...
... it's because you were by my side.
Know that.
May Allah help you with your work, my Bey.
Hopefully, Hatun.
A cart full of goods are ready.
Now we shall go to the Bazaar and get
what we deserve.
My Gündüz...
Don't take this out of your neck.
My Allah shall both protect you...
... and make hard things easy for you.
Hopefully.
Thank you, Hatun.
May Allah protect you.
You too.
My prayers are with you.
Grandfather!
May Allah bless those who left this!
Do you want to hear a secret, Karayel?
No one knows this.
You should know it.
I promised something.
A long time ago.
Maybe before I was even born.
I said "My name is Osman!"
"I will put my seal on this world!"
"I will write my name on it!"
They said I wasn't ready.
They said I was too young.
They were right.
But those who call it madness...
... don't know that...
... the charm is in my blood!
Osman didn't start running yet!
I'm still walking!
The time will come, Osman will
be up to speed...
... men from all around the world...
... will wait at my Tent's door.
Sacrifices will be made...
... everywhere my essence reaches!
How magnificent!
Karayel!
What is it?
Did you get excited too?
Come here you!
We'll watch their tricks.
We'll see them!
We'll tame ourselves.
We'll see who is friend, and who is enemy.
Before we declare the strangers as
enemies, we'll purify ourselves.
We'll clean our hearts!
We'll bring justice...
... to everywhere we step on!
We'll walk a straight path...
... without going out of Allah's way.
We'll take our beloved Bala...
... and turn our Tent into a
garden of roses.
You shall be my witness, Karayel.
I swear...
... I'll destroy the tricks of those
who try to trick us!
I'll bring justice...
... to the whole world by
dignifying the truth.
I won't bow to anyone but my Rab!
I will be the ancestor of the valiants...
... who happily sacrifice themselves!
Selamın Aleyküm
(Peace be unto you)
Ve Aleyküm Selam
(Peace be unto you too)
May I come in, Sheikh Edebali?
Come in, Alişar Bey.
As you preserved it, it must be precious.
This is from...
our commander hz Ahmed Yesevi.
The mother of pearl protects himself.
So do volume of the book.
Do you have something to say, Alişar
Bey?
Yes, Sheik Edebalı.
I say, we unite our power.
We produce, we sell.
I have contacts...
and you have the skills.
What is your goal?
If we unite, we succeed.
And we can take over the trade
around here.
It seems that this year will be arid.
If it doesn't snow, we can't feed
the animals in summer.
I suggest we go to Domaniç Mountains
and look for a upland, uncle.
Eyvallah. (Thank you)
However...
Alişar doesn't allow our mobility.
He is afraid of us.
He does.
He does, but, he wants Aygül, uncle.
He needs your friendship.
My biggest regret is about my
daughter Aygül.
I won't give my daughter to him.
Alişar Bey, you know our past.
Infidels will not leave us alone.
Don't worry about what happened recently.
I can protect us.
If necessary, I can send an army to the
bazaar.
I just need you to accept our partnership.
Only our Lord...
can give without taking something,
Alişar Bey.
What do you want in return?
Strong alliances...
involve family, and then...
the relatives, my Sheik.
For this reason...
In the name of Allah and witnessing of
our prophet...
I want your daughter Bala in marriage.
My Aygül is a delicate flower.
I worry that she may fade in this
politics fight.
You shouldn't...
give your daughter to someone like
Alişar, uncle.
That's what I think.
That's what I think too.
However, I gave my word...
I promised...
there is only one way to break
this promise.
For Kayı's goodness and our tent's
safety...
I want to give my daughter Aygül to you.
I don't plume myself, but this is really
pretty.
I will prepare these for your marriage,
my Aygül.
There is something wrong with you.
Tell me.
My father...
he doesn't trust Alişar Bey.
He doesn't want this marriage because
he thinks we will be unhappy.
Isn't that good news, my Aygül?
I know you are not in love with that man.
What can I do, Burçin?
Tell me.
Why did Osman step back?
Why did he give up?
She won't give up on Bala Hatun.
Sooner or later...
He'll bring her to the tent.
He'll marry her.
What will Aygül do?
Osman and Bala will be here
and they'll be lovers.
I'll distribute spindles on their wedding.
Then when they have kids...
I'll distribute cranberry sherbet.
No...
I can't stand it.
It kills me slowly every day.
I won't give up even if my father does.
I'll marry Alişar Bey.
I'll be the wife of...
... the Banner Lord.
I'll be happy to help my tent.
I don't care about other things.
It doesn't matter who it is...
... as long as he's not the one I want.
It's destiny, my Aygül.
It's destiny, Burçin.
But if I stay...
... my destiny will be nothing
but suffering...
Alps! Let's rest a little bit.
Protect Gündüz Bey!
Gündüz bey!
Gündüz Bey!
My Bey!
"I bear witness that there is no
deity but Allah and...
... I bear witness that Muhammad
is the messenger of God."
My Bey!
My Bey.
May I come in, Selcan Hatun?
Come in, Zöhre Hatun.
Hatuns made this. They
shared it with people.
That's yours. Enjoy while eating.
Thanks. And
may Allah bless their hands.
There's something else.
You have a problem. Tell me.
I have. I do.
But how can I tell you?
Just tell me.
Selcan Hatun.
You know, we affianced Aygül
and Alişar Bey.
Yes, I know.
As if we needed him so much.
Dündar Bey hesitates too.
He doesn't want to hurt Aygül.
But he made a promise and
he can't go back.
Promise?
It's a curse that you promised.
You can't trust this kind of people.
Yes, but he is a Banner lord.
If we don't let him marry Aygül, he'll
torture all of the tent.
It's a pity.
Zöhre, you have something in your mind.
Tell me.
Tell me so we can think about it.
I say...
Only Osman can save Aygül.
Selcan Hatun, help us.
Let's espouse Aygül and Osman.
And Osman won't suffer anymore
because of that desperate love.
And Aygül will be safe.
Only you can solve this.
The thing that you have in
mind will harm us, Zöhre.
Aygül is our one and only, of course.
But Osman is the backbone of this tent.
As to what you said...
It's too complicated.
So that we can protect our tent.
I know.
You love Bala Hatun but...
Edebali didn't allow it, Osman.
Don't ruin yourself anymore.
Talk, boy.
What do you think?
Uncle...
May I come in, my Bey?
Come in, Saltuk.
My Bey, Gündüz Bey...
He was ambushed.
- Where is he?
- In Ertuğrul Bey's tent.
My Gündüz!
Lay him down.
Hurry up!
Come on. Easy.
Bring cauters.
Gündüz...
We have to take the arrow out.
Brother...
Brother.
Gündüz. Who did this to you?
Who?
Brother.
I'll drown those people in your blood.
Brother...
Brother.
Brother! Brother!
Gündüz! No!
Aunt?
Brother.
Trade, production and bazaar are
important, Alişar Bey.
We do this for Muslims to
produce some things...
... so they won't need the infidels.
We have the same aim, my Sheikh.
That's why I want to collaborate.
If you let me...
I want your family to adorn
my mansion with tiles.
As to Bala...
Bala grew up with Islamic
monastery and laws.
Her talent is for Islamic monastery.
Not for Bey palaces.
You're the ruler of these lands.
Your tables are wide...
... pursuers are plenty...
... your burden is heavy.
Bala isn't your cup of tea.
And I don't allow it. Know that.
Your consent cuts what my
sword can't, my Sheikh.
As you wish.
But you should think about it.
My offer is always valid.
Being the groom of such a magnificent
man like you...
... is better than being the Banner Lord.
You should know that with a single word
of yours, my world changes...
... my darkness lightens up.
My Gündüz! Who did this to you?
My Allah! Please! My Gündüz!
Osman. Relax, brother.
Mother! Is my Gündüz Ağa alive?
Say something!
He's breathing!
Slowly, but he's still
breathing, thankfully!
Thankfully!
May my Rab give him back to us.
May Allah not burn our hearts.
My Allah! A magnificent man is going away.
I'm burning!
My Allah give him back to me!
Shhh. Patience, my daughter.
Patience, Ayşe.
Heat up some iron.
Aygül, the water is boiling.
Bring the rags, we need to take
the arrows out.
Aunt, tell me. Will my brother be okay?
Be prepared for everything, Osman.
Your Bey was shot right in front of you!
What were you doing, huh? Tell me!
Osman Bey, if it was a battle, we would
have died for our Bey.
Didn't you see their faces?
How many were they?
They were far away. Infidels shot him
and ran away.
They were gone before we
realised what was going on.
Zöhre, do the best of what's necessary.
Medicine, or doctors...
... I'll bring everything. As long as
my nephew recovers.
My brother wanted me
to take care of him.
Pull yourself together, my nephew!
It's time we use our senses.
- Relax.
- How can I relax, Uncle!
How can I relax while my brother
is fighting for his life?
Who is this jackal attacking our herd?
My nephew, if you're suspicious
of someone, tell me!
Here is the hardest part.
It's close to the heart.
Bismillahirrahmanirrahim
(in the name of Allah, the merciful and compassionate.)
O The Healer!
He's losing a lot of blood, mother!
Gündüz. Gündüz I'd die for you, please
open your eyes.
He's breathing. Don't worry.
He's here, Ayşe Hatun. Relax a little.
Hold on, my Gündüz. Hold on my lion!
Thank you, my Allah. Help us!
Thankfully, my Gündüz is still with us.
My Allah gave him back to us!
Aunt, it will be okay, right?
The only cure for these scars,
is to pray, Ayşe Hatun. Pray.
Aygül, we need to sear the scar.
Bismillahirrahmanirrahim
(in the name of Allah, the merciful and compassionate.)
Whoever the enemy is,
they will come to light.
Before that, no one leaves the Tent alone.
Batur!
Increase the number of guards! Increase
the frequency of night watches.
War is near! We need to be alert.
- As you wish, father.
- The Alps! Go!
Ask around for any witnesses.
I say it was the castle, father.
Only the infidels do such an ambush.
If it was the castle, there
would be no survivors.
Whoever it is, they are threatening us.
The arrows were not shot at my brother.
They were shot at the Tent,
at our hearts!
If it wasn't the castle, then only Alişar
is brave enough to do this!
- Why would alişar do something like this?
- I don't know the reason.
But, who else is brave enough to do this?
Osman, my nephew. If there's
something you know...
... tell us.
I'm wondering just like you, uncle. Order
me, and I shall look for traces.
Come on now. Come on!
Brothers, be quick, come on!
Osman Bey will be out any second.
- We'll look for traces.
- Wait now, brother.
We don't know what's going on yet.
My Boran. Don't you know Osman Bey?
He'll come out through that door, and say
"We'll look for traces!"
In his heart, he has fire which
can burn the whole world!
Thank you, brother.
If we don't turn this world into hell for
those who did this...
... our reputation will be gone.
Osman Bey, how is Gündüz Bey doing?
- He'll be okay if Allah permits.
- If Allah permits, my Bey.
My Bey! Tell us and we'll melt mountains!
Alişar learned what we did.
He wants us to pay for it.
He'll see our power! He'll see how we turn
this world into hell for traitors!
My Osman! Who does something like this?
Who tried to kill my Gündüz?
That dog Alişar who eats from
the enemy's food.
That dog Alişar?
So it's time to take our swords and go to
battle, yell and find traces?
My sides have been aching for a while,
I've been dreaming of battle for a while.
Thank you, my Rab!
We'll ambush them.
We'll show them who is
the master of the battle.
Come on then, my Osman.
Come on my lions, to the horses!
Bamsı Bey! You should stay in the tent.
We need eyes to see, ears to hear.
You know my place.
Thank you, Osman. You're right.
I know your place, thank you.
Alps!
Come on, valiants! Come on lions! Come on!
How magnificent!
Please contact us for any inquiries
turkision@gmail.com